<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to My Blog on Unmesh Mali</title>
    <link>http://localhost:64249/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome to My Blog on Unmesh Mali</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 23:16:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:64249/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Essay 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/essays/essay2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 23:16:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/essays/essay2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;essay-2&#34;&gt;Essay 2&lt;/h1&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Essay 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/essays/essay1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 23:16:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/essays/essay1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;essay-1&#34;&gt;Essay 1&lt;/h1&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 30, 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-30-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 23:16:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-30-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;week-30-2025&#34;&gt;Week 30, 2025&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;work-hahahugoshortcode37s0hbhb&#34;&gt;Work &lt;span style=&#34;float: right;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;span&gt;☆&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;span&gt;☆&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- &lt;details style=&#34;max-height: 100px; overflow: auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;summary&gt;Expand&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;/details&gt; --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This was an interesting week at CVS Health. We had a team offsite on Monday and Tuesday. I was part of the planning committee. Since most of my team is spread-out all over the USA and remote, it was nice to meet everyone in person for a change.&#xA;We also retrained a few XGBoost Models which will run in production on a test cell next week. Unfortunately, I cannot talk a lot about the specifics of the ## work I do in interest of confidentiality. Having said that, I plan on writing essays on the ## work I have done with ML and MLOps in the retail space. I have learned a lot and it would be nice to write it down and share with others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 47, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-47-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-47-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;week-47-2021&#34;&gt;Week 47, 2021&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #d73a49&#34;&gt;I hate writing, I love having written – Dorothy Parker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am writing a weekly blog after a very long break. 14 weeks long. Many&#xA;things happened and this blog would be paraphrasing the last 14 weeks. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Work has been moving slow. Since September, we have had 2 software releases&#xA;of our product. I have been involved in developing algorithms for some of the&#xA;features. One example is an algorithm for operating a group of battery&#xA;systems (with or without solar) as a virtual power plant through openADR. I&#xA;can’t be transparent about the rest of the ## work on this blog. My ## work mostly&#xA;involves identifying and fixing bugs using data, communicating results with&#xA;clients or answering their questions and concerns with eloquent&#xA;visualizations. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 33, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-33-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-33-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-33-2021&#34;&gt;Week 33, 2021&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 23, 2021&#xA;Categories: Weekly Notes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This was a slow week at Sunverge Energy. I was working from home on Wednesday&#xA;and Friday. Well, not exactly home. I was in San Rafael supporting a medical&#xA;treatment of my roommate. Working from San Rafael was a pleasant experience.&#xA;I got to take calls and do ## work from the clinic’s waiting room half the time&#xA;and from a Starbucks for the other half. Latte, Almond croissant, and data&#xA;analysis.&#xA;For the next week, I need to complete a task related to openADR. And I am&#xA;also going to make a case to my boss to allow me to contribute to software&#xA;development. The probability of me getting to ## work with software development&#xA;is low but it is worth a try.&#xA;Machine Learning Bootcamp&#xA;The week was all about deploying ML models. We deployed ML models on AWS&#xA;Elastic Beanstalk using the CLI. There were multiple assignments on PySpark,&#xA;Dash which I thought were pretty cool. All about parallel computation. We&#xA;signed up for the community edition of Databricks which allowed the use of 1&#xA;cluster. Databricks is a one-stop shop for all data needs. We used it&#xA;individually which defeats the purpose since it allows for collaboration.&#xA;About the capstone project: Me and Tiziano have completed the model testing&#xA;and tuning phase. If you don’t know, we are trying to identify fraudulent&#xA;activity from a bank’s transaction database. We researched our way into using&#xA;Unsupervised Anomaly Detection . The challenge with anomaly detection is that&#xA;you cannot measure the performance of the model. There are no metrics. I see&#xA;it more of a helper function. It can give you a lot interesting pattern in&#xA;your data but then you have to meet the model in the middle and take the&#xA;investigation further. That’s exactly what we are thinking of doing now –&#xA;just identify interesting patterns in the data and investigate further with a&#xA;different model. My task for the next week is to complete the flask app and&#xA;deploy it on AWS EB. Looking forward.&#xA;CEEW – Sustainable Mobility Research Assistant&#xA;Great news to share – I got a 3-months extension on my internship. I did a&#xA;decent job with the last assignment that I got. I don’t have the next project&#xA;yet. Abhinav (my manager at CEEW) gave me a list of project to do which I&#xA;listed in the last blog (Week 31) but I found out later that they are all&#xA;policy ## projects. I am thinking a lot of internet research and document&#xA;writing with these ## projects which I am not looking forward to. I think I am&#xA;going to skip on all of those and find a project with data analysis or&#xA;machine learning. Fingers crossed. Let’s see how this internship shapes my&#xA;career going forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 31, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-31-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-31-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-31-2021&#34;&gt;Week 31, 2021&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 9, 2021&#xA;Categories: Weekly Notes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The last two weeks have been productive at ## work. Just usual stuff. Putting&#xA;out fires, making progress with ongoing ## projects and sprints, asset&#xA;monitoring and management, and closely working with customers to answer&#xA;questions with data and solve their issues if any. I have learned to be&#xA;flexible at this company and I am not overly concerned about what I do day to&#xA;day.&#xA;Machine Learning Bootcamp&#xA;Decent week at the Bootcamp. In the last 2 weeks, we focussed on GAN models –&#xA;Generative Adversarial Networks and Time series and Sequence modeling. One&#xA;application of cycleGAN that we explored in our live session assignment is&#xA;Uber’s use of the model to generate nighttime and extreme weather event&#xA;images to train their autonomous driving models. In Sequence modeling, we&#xA;explored RNN modes to predict outcomes of online browsing sessions for&#xA;Cosmetics company. Pretty cool stuff –&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/unmeshmali25/Sequence-Modelling-Cosmetics-&#34;&gt;https://github.com/unmeshmali25/Sequence-Modelling-Cosmetics-&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;Dataset/blob/main/Sequence_Learning_on_Cosmetics_Data_4B_v1_Unmesh.ipynb&#xA;CEEW – Sustainable Mobility Research Assistant&#xA;I managed to solve the deployment problem with the web app to rank bus&#xA;shelters in India using Computer Vision. The problem of deployment failure&#xA;with PythonAnywhere, DigitalOcean, and AWS ElasticBeanstalk  was memory&#xA;limit. The virtual environment containing the web app, required dependencies&#xA;, and the trained ML model sat at 1.4GB  of space. Each of the above&#xA;mentioned FREE third party hosting services allow for not more than 512MB .&#xA;And, Heroku  no longer supports Python-3.7.6  which is required (strictly) to&#xA;run the ImageAI  python package. That sucked.&#xA;The solution I came up with is more of a hack than a scalable solution. I&#xA;deployed the model on my local machine as a WSGI server  using the gunicorn&#xA;python package and exposed my IP address over the internet using secure HTTPs&#xA;URL. I used a third party tunneling service called gw.run . The last&#xA;remaining task in this project is to transfer the app, model, and&#xA;dependencies to a windows computer of my project supervisor. He has a good&#xA;GPU on his laptop and we might be able to speed up the processing. Right now,&#xA;our model takes about 5 seconds to process 1 image. I assume the city of&#xA;Delhi has around 2000 bus shelters or more. That’s 3 hours to rank all the&#xA;bus shelters in Delhi. Now Imagine that the state or central government&#xA;install cameras on each of these bus shelters, those cameras will be feeding&#xA;video and images of bus shelters all day long. With that kind of&#xA;infrastructure, our model would be very inefficient.&#xA;After completion of the project last week, I expressed my enthusiasm to ## work&#xA;on other ingoing ## projects at CEEW and they sent me a list of ## projects to&#xA;choose from. Next week, I will spend some time on preliminary research to&#xA;choose a project. Enabling multi-modal freight logistics in India  sounds&#xA;like an awesome project. Another interesting project is Addressing fuel tax&#xA;revenue loss with high EV penetration . Exciting times ahead with CEEW.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 29, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-29-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-29-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-29-2021&#34;&gt;Week 29, 2021&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 26, 2021&#xA;Categories: Weekly Notes&#xA;“But man is not made for defeat,” he said. “A man can be destroyed but&#xA;not defeated.” &#xA;– Ernest Hemingway&#xA;The last three to four weeks have been defeating. Sorry to start this blog on&#xA;a sad note but it’s true. I have bitten off more that I can chew but I have&#xA;to finish all the things that I have started.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 24, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-24-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-24-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-24-2021&#34;&gt;Week 24, 2021&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;June 21, 2021&#xA;Categories: Weekly Notes&#xA;The punches you miss are the ones that&#xA;wear you out.&#xA;Boxing trainer Angelo Dundee&#xA;I quit the Fire Progression Prediction project this week ! I wasn’t making&#xA;any progress on that project. The last update I have on the project is from&#xA;Week 16. I was carrying that burden in my head without any action on it. It&#xA;became an energy sink. Quitting that project meant letting go of a lot of&#xA;future possibilities, burning bridges with professors, etc. It was a hard&#xA;decision to make. But now that I have done it, it is time to focus my energy&#xA;on the task at hand. Enough time to cry at night eh?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 22, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-22-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-22-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-22-2021&#34;&gt;Week 22, 2021&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;June 13, 2021&#xA;Categories: Weekly Notes&#xA;Those who do not know how to fight worry&#xA;die young&#xA;Dale Carnegie&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was focused on two things at ## work this week. First, problem-solving –&#xA;triaging bugs, recreating them in demo environments, and passing onto&#xA;software developers to fix those bugs in production. Second, I am supporting&#xA;sales team of the company. We recently signed one of our biggest ## projects in&#xA;terms of number of battery systems installed. The plan is to now use this&#xA;approved project as a fulcrum to land more ## projects from utilities in the US&#xA;and beyond. It’s a new area for me. It’s interesting.&#xA;Machine Learning Bootcamp&#xA;Tesla Car Sales Prediction: The task was to use sales data for Quarter 1 and&#xA;2 from Tesla, and predict the sales of the given models for the next 2&#xA;quarters. We had data for 2019. We trained the model on Q1 and Q2 sales, and&#xA;tested the model on Q3 and Q4. This was a test to compare different&#xA;regression models. We tried Gradient Descent, Normal Equations, Generalized&#xA;Linear Models (non-linear regression), and Random Forest Regression. We&#xA;compared the results based on RMSE and R2 scores. Random Forest Regressor&#xA;with 100 estimators gave us the best results out of all.&#xA;Walmart Labs Funnel Analysis – The task was to classify purchasing customers&#xA;vs non-purchasing customers on their e-commerce store. Given were 15 features&#xA;which included number of sessions, number of carts, max price of cart, time&#xA;of day, day of week etc. After some pre-processing, like one-hot encoding all&#xA;the categorical features, we dropped features with high correlation. We tried&#xA;feature selection with p-value as well. We then used Random Forest to get&#xA;feature rails/importances for each feature. Afterwards we ran the processed&#xA;data through multiple classification algorithms – logistic regression, SVM,&#xA;Neural networks etc. The comparison of each of these models using the&#xA;confusion matrix was really cool. Using metrics like Accuracy, Precision,&#xA;Recall, F1-score gave us a complete picture of the performance of the models.&#xA;CEEW – Sustainable Mobility Research Assistant&#xA;This week at CEEW, we reached a milestone in trying to build a Rapid Bus&#xA;Shelter Assessment model. The code we have built so far – segments objects&#xA;from an image – people, bus, car, animals, motorcycles etc. This is actually&#xA;done by the pre-trained YOLO model. Much thanks to Tensorflow and whoever&#xA;trained the model. Our code now takes this segmented image and applied&#xA;certain “rules” to classify the image as Accessible/Inaccessible or&#xA;Safe/Unsafe. The results are pretty cool given that we have less than 2 weeks&#xA;to finish this.&#xA;Dashboard : The next task for this project is building a web app for this&#xA;service. I am using Dash/Plotly packages from Python to achieve this. Let’s&#xA;see how this implementation goes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 21, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-21-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-21-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-21-2021&#34;&gt;Week 21, 2021&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;June 1, 2021&#xA;Categories: Weekly Notes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I spent around 40% of the time in troubleshooting a bug in production.&#xA;Another 30% in project management for the new contract. The remaining time&#xA;was spent in creating database metrics mapping to clients internal&#xA;measurement points. This task was challenging in that it required me to look&#xA;at tiny details and make my way through incomplete and incoherent documents.&#xA;No analytics or optimization at all this week.&#xA;Machine Learning Bootcamp&#xA;This week I learned and applied concepts of Suport Vector Machines for an&#xA;image recognition project. Another project was to perform Credit Assessment&#xA;for a bank to predict how likely a candidate is to receive loan from the&#xA;bank.&#xA;The image recognition problem introduced me to the concept of Principal&#xA;Component Analysis for feature selection and making pipelines to pre-process&#xA;data. We also used GridSearchCV to find the best possible combinations of&#xA;hyper-parameters like Gamma, C etc.&#xA;And the Bank Credit Assessment had over 35 features including age, education,&#xA;sex, duration, balance, etc. There were a lot of features and we used Pearson&#xA;Correlation, and P-value to get rid of highly correlated features. p-value&#xA;kept 17 features out of 37. Then we introduced Lasso Regressor which brought&#xA;down the features to 2. And then Random Forest Classifier algorithm from&#xA;sklearn package did the rest.&#xA;CEEW – Sustainable Mobility Research Assistant&#xA;We decided to go with Object Detection pre-trained model to rank the bus&#xA;stops based on accessibility and security. The YOLO model (You Only Look&#xA;Once) from Tensorflow supposedly works best however, recent upgrades to other&#xA;dependent packages like numpy and Keras have rendered the model unworkable. I&#xA;felt frustration after upgrading and downgrading many packages but I still&#xA;failed. I tried to find other pre-trained models but I was advised against it&#xA;by the project lead. I hope the following week brings great news.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 20, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-20-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-20-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-20-2021&#34;&gt;Week 20, 2021&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 25, 2021&#xA;Categories: Weekly Notes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-was-slow-this-week-i-worked-on-and-finished-only-one-analytical&#34;&gt;Work was slow this week. I worked on and finished only one analytical&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;project. Rest of the tasks were reading, working with others with&#xA;troubleshooting, and brainstorming a control logic to minimize green house&#xA;gas emissions for a group of houses. I wish I was doing more analytically&#xA;technical tasks but it is what it is.&#xA;Machine Learning Bootcamp&#xA;This bootcamp got very busy super fast. Currently studying linear regression&#xA;with all its nuances. Uni-variate regression, multi-variate regression, using&#xA;gradient descent to converge a model. Also completed 3 ## projects in the last&#xA;week. Covid-19 infections predictions for Chicago, Covid-19 international&#xA;cases and tests analysis and prediction, housing prices prediction using&#xA;gradient descent. Here’s the link to my Github profile where I have uploaded&#xA;the ## projects. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/unmeshmali25&#34;&gt;https://github.com/unmeshmali25&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;CEEW – Sustainable Mobility Research Assistant&#xA;I started helping out CEEW with a hackathon type competition. The project is&#xA;to make rapid assessment of bus stops in terms of accessibility and safety.&#xA;So, looking at things like private cars parked in front of the bus stop,&#xA;benches to sit on, curbs around the bus stop, lights etc. The project is on a&#xA;very tight schedule. We have just over a month to deliver on this project. I&#xA;started working on collecting data. Chasing 2 options right now. 1) Get&#xA;locations of all the bus stops in an Indian city and programmatically&#xA;download Google Street View Images at those locations. 2) Use web scrapping&#xA;to download images that show up in google image search after typing in “bus&#xA;stops in India” keyword. I have executed on the latter option. Next week,&#xA;we’ll have to focus on using pre-trained models to run on our test images.&#xA;Given that we don’t have a lot of time, going with pre-trained neural network&#xA;models is out best bet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 19, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-19-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-19-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-19-2021&#34;&gt;Week 19, 2021&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 20, 2021&#xA;Categories: Weekly Notes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Worked with OpenADR implementation and the problems associated with it.&#xA;Worked with QA engineers to recreate and solve some of these problems. A lot&#xA;of collaboration this week. I enjoyed it. Also, we commissioned a new client,&#xA;so fulfilling all data requests and building dashboards on Tableau to view&#xA;day-to-day operations. These dashboards also help us troubleshoot in near&#xA;real time. Attending meetings with the client to answer their questions and&#xA;note their concerns. A fun week ## work. Now that most of our employees are&#xA;coming to office, a lot of interesting conversations keep me entertained&#xA;throughout the ## work day.&#xA;Machine Learning Bootcamp&#xA;Began this bootcamp with a 6 hour live online session on Saturday. Many&#xA;interesting people are part of this bootcamp. Learning/coding together is a&#xA;lot more engaging and rewarding. I missed that. We have started out the&#xA;course with univariate and multivariate regressions. Mostly working on COVID-&#xA;19 data around the world. The new thing I learned this week was Variance&#xA;Inflation Factor (VIF) that is used to find co-linearity between features.&#xA;Cool stuff. Check this out: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/unmeshmali25/COVID19-&#34;&gt;https://github.com/unmeshmali25/COVID19-&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;Prediction-Chicago-Hands-on-Regression&#xA;CEEW – Sustainable Mobility Research Assistant&#xA;Just went through the HR induction. Also got an overview of some of the&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 18, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-18-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-18-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-18-2021&#34;&gt;Week 18, 2021&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 16, 2021&#xA;Categories: Weekly Notes&#xA;Came down with the flu this week. Couldn’t get a lot of ## work/reading/exercise&#xA;done. I don’t know why I am even writing this blog with nothing to show for&#xA;the week.&#xA;Be-dili kya yunhi din guzar jayenge&#xA;Sirf zinda rahe hum to mar jaenge&#xA;Jaun Eliya&#xA;Apart from the unproductive week, I have two major news to share. I have been&#xA;selected for the Research intern position at Council on Energy, Environment,&#xA;and Water which is going to be remote. And I am starting my Machine Learning&#xA;Bootcamp at FourthBrain next week. I fear that I might have taken up too much&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 17, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-17-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-17-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-17-2021&#34;&gt;Week 17, 2021&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 3, 2021&#xA;Categories: Weekly Notes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week was off to a great start. I was given a documentation assignment.&#xA;While completing the assignment, I learned all I can about a Smart Home&#xA;management protocol called Echonet Lite. It was fun to read about it. Got&#xA;involved in a couple more interesting ## projects in the company.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Practical Programming for Strength Training | Mark Rippertoe and Andy Baker&#xA;I finished this book over this week. Read close to 200 pages. The book mostly&#xA;talks about different training methods adopted by different trainers all over&#xA;the world in the last century. These include the Texas Method, Dynamic Effort&#xA;Method, The Split Routine among others. I don’t know which one I’ll end up&#xA;adopting in my training routine. I like the Texas method the best so far.&#xA;Splitting the week between 3 training days. One day is high intensity day,&#xA;next is high volume day, and the last is light day with low volume and low&#xA;intensity. I’ll use this technique for the next few months.&#xA;Deep Learning with PyTorch | Eli Stevens, Luca Antiga, and Thomas Viehman&#xA;Read around 20 pages of this book. The book is now walking me through image&#xA;classification using deep learning. Interesting stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 16, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-16-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-16-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-16-2021&#34;&gt;Week 16, 2021&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 26, 2021&#xA;Categories: Weekly Notes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-was-decent-this-week-nothing-creative-i-provided-some-data-analysis-to&#34;&gt;Work was decent this week. Nothing creative. I provided some data analysis to&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;make/change certain decisions for our software. One good thing was that I am&#xA;getting involved in software project management. It is new to me and I’m&#xA;excited to learn all about it. Looking forward to a productive and creative&#xA;next week.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Practical Programming for Strength Training | Mark Rippertoe and Andy Baker&#xA;Making super slow progress with this book. On Page 220 out of 400. This week&#xA;the book talked about the Texas Method where you start the week with high&#xA;intensity weight lifting, the next session is high volume with slightly lower&#xA;intensity, and the last workout session of the week is low intensity and low&#xA;volume. Good technique to know. I have also heard Joe Rogan talk about the&#xA;Texas method on his podcast. Would love to try it out. I just wish I would&#xA;have read a lot more of this book.&#xA;Deep Learning with PyTorch | Eli Stevens, Luca Antiga, and Thomas Viehman&#xA;I read only a few pages of this book this week. This week was busy with ## work&#xA;and side ## projects that were mentally taxing and this book just would have&#xA;been too much mental ## work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 15, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-15-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-15-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;week-15-2021&#34;&gt;Week 15, 2021&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A wonderful week at ## work. I started working on a Demand Response project. The&#xA;US electric utilities use OpenADR protocol for Demand Response. Any company&#xA;offering grid services must follow the OpenADR standard. Getting good hands-&#xA;on experience with it. I have learned a lot this week which I can’t share&#xA;here. I also spent some time networking with people outside the company.&#xA;Attended the Clean Energy Leadership Institute’s (CELI) webinar and got a&#xA;chance to hear some cool people talk.&#xA;Side Project&#xA;Got a chance this week to ## work on the Fire Progression Prediction project. I&#xA;am still working on creating a pipeline for the fire data. At this point, we&#xA;have around 183 unique fires in the United States over the last 10 years. The&#xA;figure below shows the location of each of the fires. You might notice that&#xA;each fire is a box. That box is part of the pre-processing. To feed data into&#xA;the Neural Network, each input must be standardized. Each box in our project&#xA;has the same size such that even the largest fire is contained within that&#xA;box. Given that I am new to Google Earth Engine, this was a tough task to do&#xA;but Professors at USF helped immensely. Next week hoping to finish the pre-&#xA;processing completely and move on to working on the Neural Network.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 14, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-14-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-14-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-14-2021&#34;&gt;Week 14, 2021&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 12, 2021&#xA;Categories: Weekly Notes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sunverge is slowly and safely opening its SF office to employees. This week I&#xA;went into the office first 3 days of the week. I ended up getting more ## work&#xA;done but also more tired at the end of the day than when I am working from&#xA;home. I guess I got used to working from home. I hope I adapt fast to working&#xA;from office everyday. Spent some time of the week helping the customer&#xA;support team with troubleshooting. Other time I was either working with the&#xA;sales staff with proposals or revisiting already signed customer&#xA;deliverables.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 13, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-13-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-13-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-13-2021&#34;&gt;Week 13, 2021&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 5, 2021&#xA;Categories: Weekly Notes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week I learned that as a data analyst/scientist, it is better to be&#xA;doubtful and right than be confident and wrong. It saves a lot of time of&#xA;other teams/employees when you don’t submit confident and wrong assignments&#xA;forward. Performed some exploratory analysis along with asset monitoring and&#xA;providing research support for writing business proposals. A busy week at&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 12, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-12-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-12-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-12-2021&#34;&gt;Week 12, 2021&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 29, 2021&#xA;Categories: Weekly Notes&#xA;This was a tough week. I felt a general lack of motivation in all aspects of&#xA;life. There was enormous mental friction in doing even the simplest of tasks&#xA;like laundry. I am not sure why. But just the realization that there is a&#xA;mental blockage reduced its potential and I was able to control some of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The week was all about troubleshooting with remote diagnostics, asset&#xA;monitoring and product documentation. Also spent time on delivering&#xA;performance and testing reports to customers. A week of less programming and&#xA;statistical analysis and more client-facing ## work.&#xA;I am a huge electric vehicle nerd and thus my YouTube feed is full of EV&#xA;news. Some EV range testers ran the Tesla Model 3, Mustang Mach-e, and the VW&#xA;ID.4 beyond their 0% State of Charge. They found that the Tesla drove 22&#xA;miles after reaching 0% whereas the Mach-e only did 6 miles. I just thought&#xA;that was super interesting. Battery pack manufacturers usually leave some&#xA;room at the bottom SOC to protect the batteries. SOC estimation is an&#xA;interesting problem. Some battery manufacturers map it to the cell voltage&#xA;(since there is a linear relationship between the battery voltage and its&#xA;SOC). I wonder what Tesla does.&#xA;Side Project&#xA;Virtually met with one of the professors to resolve a problem with my Google&#xA;Earth Engine code. Right now I am tasked at creating a pipeline to provide&#xA;the right type of data to the neural network that is also currently in the&#xA;works by another project mate. We got 180 fires and after a lot of pre-&#xA;processing we are very close to exporting rastors (images) of the fires from&#xA;Google Earth Engine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 11, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-11-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-11-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-11-2021&#34;&gt;Week 11, 2021&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 22, 2021&#xA;Categories: Weekly Notes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Faster along, further together” – The quote sums up this week at ## work.&#xA;Working with QA engineers to test the integration, configurations, and&#xA;algorithm for a project that was worked on by many developers at different&#xA;times, tested by different QA engineers and approved by another product&#xA;person. The software development process can’t get more complicated than that&#xA;now, can it? I can’t appreciate enough the tools in Atlasssian product suite.&#xA;Did you know that Atlasssian is an Australian company? One of the very few&#xA;tech companies in Australia that has had a major impact on the world&#xA;especially the silicon valley ecosystem. It’s a fascinating story (Listed to&#xA;the podcast if interested). Also spent some time on websites of electric&#xA;utilities to provide some market research support to the sales staff. A&#xA;decent week.&#xA;Side Project&#xA;I am volunteering with Professors from University of San Francisco (my Alma&#xA;Mater) to ## work on a project that involves predicting the progression&#xA;(direction and speed) of wild fires once they have been ignited. The project&#xA;is part of the MAGIX lab at USF where they ## work on solving complex societal&#xA;problems using Machine Learning and Deep Learning and publish papers. Our&#xA;project involves using deep learning to do the prediction. More details on&#xA;the project can be found in the ## projects section. Spent just over 3 hours&#xA;this week on the project mostly researching.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 10, 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-10-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/posts/weekly/week-10-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-10-2021&#34;&gt;Week 10, 2021&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 11, 2021&#xA;Categories: Weekly Notes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Working on multiple things like always. I have a couple technical ## projects in&#xA;hand that involve Python and Java programming. I also learned Docker to be&#xA;able to deploy those ## projects. On the client-facing side, delivered on some&#xA;data and Tableau dashboard requests. Spent a lot of time with the QA team to&#xA;test out new deliverables. Not the best but a fun week at ## work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to My Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64249/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64249/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcome to my corner of the internet. Here I mostly write about this and that.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am currently working as a Machine Learning Engineer (or internally referred to Senior Data Scientist) at CVS Health. Specifically I work in the Offer Engine team of CVS Retail to make customers shop more and often by giving right offers to the right customers. The work sounds simple but at the scale of many millions of customers and working in a Fortune 500 company with its rate of change limitations, the personal, technical challenges and nuances quickly add up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
